<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Dark-Kernel</title>
    <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Dark-Kernel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:48:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://patel-sumit.web.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ansible</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:48:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/ansible/</guid>
      <description>What is ansible? It is a automation tool.
uses:
configuration Install applications on server configuring firewall on server/VMs we can configure multiple things in one single playbook, like: db,server, etc. needs:
Uses ssh for the connectivity, no agent needed. Environment setup Using virtual to setup one ansible main machine and two other which will act as server. we will be creating first an template machine and then will clone it for new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 20:10:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>Terraform Terraform is a infrastructure as a code tool to build an define cloud structure as well as onprem resources with json like easy to read configuration files. It can manage from low-level components to high-level components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 20:10:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/terraform/</guid>
      <description>Terraform Terraform is a infrastructure as a code tool to build an define cloud structure as well as onprem resources with json like easy to read configuration files. It can manage from low-level components to high-level components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 21:03:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/search/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ ln -s you .</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 20:47:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/contact/</guid>
      <description> Suggestions ? Submit Connect with me on </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ whoami</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 19:54:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I am Sumit Patel A Linux enthusiast As a Linux enthusiast, I have always been fascinated by the power and flexibility of open-source software. I enjoy exploring the world of programming and learning new commands and tools that help me become a more efficient developer. Whether I am creating scripts to automate routine tasks or delving into the intricacies of cloud servers, I remain committed to refining my craft and expanding my knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$ whoami _</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 19:54:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/blog/</guid>
      <description>About me $whoami</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/docker-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/docker-post/</guid>
      <description>Docker Docker is an open source containerization platform. It enables developers to package applications into containers—standardized executable components combining application source code with the operating system (OS) libraries and dependencies required to run that code in any environment. Containers simplify delivery of distributed applications, and have become increasingly popular as organizations shift to cloud-native development and hybrid multicloud environments.
Containers are made possible by process isolation and virtualization capabilities built into the Linux kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CronJob</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/cronjob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 19:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/cronjob/</guid>
      <description>CronJob Cron is a job scheduling utility present in Unix like systems. The crond daemon enables cron functionality and runs in background. The cron reads the crontab (cron tables) for running predefined scripts. Cron is a system that helps Linux users to schedule any task. However, a cron job is any defined task to run in a given time period. It can be a shell script or a simple bash command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bettercap</title>
      <link>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/bettercap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 18:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patel-sumit.web.app/posts/bettercap/</guid>
      <description>Bettercap Framework Bettercap is a powerfull, easily extensible and portable framework written in Go which aims to offer to security researches, redteamers and reverse engineers an easy to use, all-in-one solution with all the features they might possibly need for performing reconnaissance and attacking WiFi networks, Bluetooth Low Energy devices, wireless HID devices and IPv4/IPv6 networks.
Main Features WiFi networks scanning, deauthentication attack, clientless PMKID association attack and automatic WPA/WPA2 client handshakes capture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
